<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-29T09:34:13+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The SXWVN Website</title><subtitle>I make music in my free time, but I&apos;m currently studying in the IT field.  The paranoid scientist meet the vulnerable artist. Welcome. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2025-04-24T10:16:09+07:00</published><updated>2025-04-24T10:16:09+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll"><![CDATA[<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ambition, Competition, and Disappointment</title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/ambition-competition-and-disappointment" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ambition, Competition, and Disappointment" /><published>2025-02-25T08:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2025-02-25T08:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/ambition-competition-and-disappointment</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/ambition-competition-and-disappointment"><![CDATA[<style>
    .video-wrapper {
        width: 100%;       
        overflow: hidden;   
    }
    
    .video-wrapper video {
        width: 100%;        
        height: auto;       
        display: block;     
    }
</style>

<div class="video-wrapper">
    <video controls="">
        <source src="https://sxwvn-website-be.onrender.com/api/video/ABCD.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    </video>
</div>

<p>Growing up in an Asian household means two things:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Your parents expect you to become a doctor</li>
  <li>You were told your hobbies (especially if it’s artistic) mean nothing</li>
</ul>

<p>Jokes aside, the first thing sort of happened to me. Look, I’m not sure where to draw the line between directly and indirectly giving your child expectations. Because unlike some of my friends where it’s obvious that the path they chose today is <em>forced</em> upon them by their parents or teachers (under the guise of “you have so much potential!”), neither of my parent figures ever explicitly told me I <em>have</em> to strive for more, more, and more. I’m well aware those words come from my own self, but it has to come from somewhere, right?</p>

<p>Yes, maybe. I’m not sure. I’m not really in the mood to make an essay about how grandiose means nothing to me, or that believing in one’s dreams is the most foolish thing to do, or how quotes such as “dream so high you’ll fall among the stars” feel kinda weird to me. However, I have to say: I’m really tired of feeling not good enough. I want to see life as a road trip, not a race. I feel like most of my achievements are 80% luck and 20% hard work. I want to understand how the world works just for the sake of curiosity, not because I’m driven (or destined) to play hero and change the world.</p>

<p>I don’t know how I got here. I’m thankful, absolutely! But I never planned any of this. It just happens. Sometimes, most of the times, it does NOT happen. So please, stop looking at me through a pair of rose-tinted glasses. We’re all descendents of men here.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="video" /><category term="music" /><category term="yapping" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your browser does not support the video tag. Growing up in an Asian household means two things: Your parents expect you to become a doctor You were told your hobbies (especially if it’s artistic) mean nothing Jokes aside, the first thing sort of happened to me. Look, I’m not sure where to draw the line between directly and indirectly giving your child expectations. Because unlike some of my friends where it’s obvious that the path they chose today is forced upon them by their parents or teachers (under the guise of “you have so much potential!”), neither of my parent figures ever explicitly told me I have to strive for more, more, and more. I’m well aware those words come from my own self, but it has to come from somewhere, right? Yes, maybe. I’m not sure. I’m not really in the mood to make an essay about how grandiose means nothing to me, or that believing in one’s dreams is the most foolish thing to do, or how quotes such as “dream so high you’ll fall among the stars” feel kinda weird to me. However, I have to say: I’m really tired of feeling not good enough. I want to see life as a road trip, not a race. I feel like most of my achievements are 80% luck and 20% hard work. I want to understand how the world works just for the sake of curiosity, not because I’m driven (or destined) to play hero and change the world. I don’t know how I got here. I’m thankful, absolutely! But I never planned any of this. It just happens. Sometimes, most of the times, it does NOT happen. So please, stop looking at me through a pair of rose-tinted glasses. We’re all descendents of men here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Villain In Red Suit</title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/villain-in-red-suit" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Villain In Red Suit" /><published>2024-10-14T10:20:20+07:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T10:20:20+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/villain-in-red-suit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/villain-in-red-suit"><![CDATA[<style>
    .video-wrapper {
        width: 100%;       
        overflow: hidden;   
    }
    
    .video-wrapper video {
        width: 100%;        
        height: auto;       
        display: block;     
    }
</style>

<div class="video-wrapper">
    <video controls="">
        <source src="https://sxwvn-website-be.onrender.com/api/video/VIRS.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    </video>
</div>

<p>The villain in red suit is a manifestation of my childhood trauma. I picture them wearing a bright red suit because of redacted reasons that will serve as a clue to OSINT my real identity. Let’s just say, that’s what they like to wear. Which is kind of unfortunate because I always thought my favorite color is red (I don’t know what’s my current favorite color anymore…).</p>

<p>I first wrote this song in February of 2021 when the wound was still fresh. I ocassionally listen to the song/watch the music video (especially when developing this website to make sure the video loads properly), and all I got from it was just sadness. In contrast, <em>Ambition, Competition, and Disappointment</em> resolves in a hopeful note. Well, I mean what do you expect when you quite literally traumatize a 16 year old kid? IN THE MIDDLE OF THE PANDEMIC as well…</p>

<p>To quote one of my favorite artist of all time:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Just 21 so I’m young and I’m stupid</p>

  <p>Only 16, yeah I think you should’ve known</p>

  <p>I think you fucked me up.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="video" /><category term="music" /><category term="yapping" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your browser does not support the video tag. The villain in red suit is a manifestation of my childhood trauma. I picture them wearing a bright red suit because of redacted reasons that will serve as a clue to OSINT my real identity. Let’s just say, that’s what they like to wear. Which is kind of unfortunate because I always thought my favorite color is red (I don’t know what’s my current favorite color anymore…). I first wrote this song in February of 2021 when the wound was still fresh. I ocassionally listen to the song/watch the music video (especially when developing this website to make sure the video loads properly), and all I got from it was just sadness. In contrast, Ambition, Competition, and Disappointment resolves in a hopeful note. Well, I mean what do you expect when you quite literally traumatize a 16 year old kid? IN THE MIDDLE OF THE PANDEMIC as well… To quote one of my favorite artist of all time: Just 21 so I’m young and I’m stupid Only 16, yeah I think you should’ve known I think you fucked me up.]]></summary></entry></feed>