<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The SXWVN Website</title><subtitle>I make music in my free time, but I&apos;m currently studying in the IT field.  The paranoid scientist meet the vulnerable artist. Welcome. </subtitle><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-12-may-journal-12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-12-may-journal-12</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-12-may-journal-12"><![CDATA[<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>\begin{document}
\section{Software Simulation}
\subsection{Simulation of One Vehicle}
\begin{figure}[h]
    \centering
    \includegraphics[width=0.4\textwidth]{fig/one-slow.png}
    \caption{Rule-abiding Vehicle Simulation
}
    \label{fig:one-slow}
\end{figure}

\begin{figure}[h]
    \centering
    \includegraphics[width=0.4\textwidth]{fig/one-slow.png}
    \caption{Simulation of a Vehicle Breaking the Rules}
    \label{fig:one-tight}
\end{figure}

In this software simulation, we use Pygame software-based simulation. The figure above shows the simulation results for one vehicle passing in one lane. There are two sensors that can calculate the speed of the vehicle and if the vehicle does not exceed the speed limit, which is 30 km/h then the Smart Speed Bump is not active and the camera also does not take pictures of the vehicle (Figure \ref{fig:one-slow}). However, if the vehicle is detected to be exceeding the speed limit by both sensors, the Smart Speed Bump is active and the camera also takes a picture of the vehicle illustrated by a red color change on the camera (Figure \ref{fig:one-fast}). Each simulation will record vehicle's speed on the speed graph.
\end{document}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>How is this real? Seriously.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-13-may-journal-13" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-13-may-journal-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-13-may-journal-13"><![CDATA[<p>I have so many things to do. Going Insane… I want to take a break. Going Insane… The future is uncertain. Going Insane… I don’t know if I’ll make it. Going Insane… What if I die, What if I live?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-14-may-journal-14" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-14-may-journal-14</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-14-may-journal-14"><![CDATA[<p>I guess this is it. This is goodbye. I can’t believe this but I’ve reached the end, and I’m still alive. In fact, I’m more alive. That’s cool.</p>

<p>This will sound corny but today’s goodbye marks the start of a new phase. A phase associated with big desires, with impossible missions, with high stakes decisions. It would’ve been nice if I could <strong>stay</strong>. If I could just be safe and satisfied with small desires; graduate, get a job at a local business, start a family, and settle near my hometown. But for reasons I don’t want to share publicly (at this point you’ve figured why), I just can’t afford that kind of lifestyle.</p>

<p>I will always be on the run, and that’s alright.</p>

<p>Can’t deny this feeling but there are parts of me who really just want to stand still. Let the cold breeze soothes my aching bones. Let the laughter and cries of my loved ones be the background noise of my day. Stay, even for a second. Stay.</p>

<p>I want to stay.
Will I ever find someone, somewhere, somehow that will let me taste my small desire? Maybe this world is too broken, too full of snakes to trust, too full of idle NPC under a rigged system unable to do anything.</p>

<p>I want to stay, but so far east I’m westbound.</p>

<p>I was thinking maybe if we’re living in a simulation; we look the same (or not having any looks at all, just a floating entity), and speak the same made up language, maybe we’ll finally unite as one species. But then I thought, well what if we start to develop our own ways of life, habits, cultures, and arbitrary rules of in-group and out-group? I think humanity’s bound to do that.</p>

<p>Maybe we’re bound to hurt each other, guided by our primal fear of the unknown. Maybe it’s survival.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-15-may-journal-15" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-15-may-journal-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-15-may-journal-15"><![CDATA[<p>A quick glance to my weather app showed that the next few days will have heavy storm all over. It’s thunder season!</p>

<p>I sure hope this will not affect that big thing that’ll happen over the weekend (Foreshadowing)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-16-may-journal-16" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-16-may-journal-16</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-16-may-journal-16"><![CDATA[<h2 id="under-construction">UNDER CONSTRUCTION!!!</h2>

<p>When the album does come, and in an unlikely event of it blowing up, the OG’s will remember that this song has long been published before the <em>official</em> release date!</p>

<p>If everything we ever had has come to and end, well I hope it ends in a good note.
If this chapter of our lives has come to a close, well I don’t know, I wish I didn’t have to go</p>

<p>Cause I don’t want to be hurt
Yet I never learn
To put up a fight
And set my boundary right</p>

<p>Everything we ever called our home has always been a mess
So I bid my farewell and God bless.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-17-may-journal-17" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-17-may-journal-17</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-17-may-journal-17"><![CDATA[<p>I do not want to talk about this day. I’m physically stuck and I’m mentally somewhere else. If there’s a silver lining at least I don’t die yet.</p>

<p>Hey, can we please stop looking at things as if they have a hidden lesson?</p>

<p><em>“Oh, you’re such a brave and stong kid for doing that! This surely taught you how to be an independent adult and you sure did go through it well!”</em></p>

<p>No. Can I just be pissed about this? None of these were not my fault. It didn’t teach me shit.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-18-may-journal-18" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-18-may-journal-18</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-18-may-journal-18"><![CDATA[<h3 id="remember">Remember</h3>
<style>
    .video-wrapper {
        width: 100%;       
        overflow: hidden;   
    }
    
    .video-wrapper video {
        width: 100%;        
        height: auto;       
        display: block;     
    }
</style>

<div class="video-wrapper">
    <video controls="">
        <source src="https://sxwvn-website-be.onrender.com/api/video/Remember%20(2024).mp4" type="video/mp4" />
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    </video>
</div>

<h3 id="fly">Fly</h3>
<style>
    .video-wrapper {
        width: 100%;       
        overflow: hidden;   
    }
    
    .video-wrapper video {
        width: 100%;        
        height: auto;       
        display: block;     
    }
</style>

<div class="video-wrapper">
    <video controls="">
        <source src="https://sxwvn-website-be.onrender.com/api/video/FLY.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    </video>
</div>

<h3 id="i-love-you-platonically">I Love You, Platonically</h3>
<style>
    .video-wrapper {
        width: 100%;       
        overflow: hidden;   
    }
    
    .video-wrapper video {
        width: 100%;        
        height: auto;       
        display: block;     
    }
</style>

<div class="video-wrapper">
    <video controls="">
        <source src="https://sxwvn-website-be.onrender.com/api/video/spes.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    </video>
</div>

<h3 id="what-the-hell-are-these">What the hell are these?</h3>
<p>Collection of music videos I made for my friends birthdays because I was too broke to buy them something. It’s a fun challenge too, to try and compose one song in a week and animate a music video to accompany it. I did it 3 (technically 4) times and yet I only nailed the timeliness aspect once.</p>

<p>Who would’ve guessed, turns out animating and video editing take a long time! /s</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-19-may-journal-19" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-19-may-journal-19</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-19-may-journal-19"><![CDATA[<p>Paradoxically I think the most faithful, loyal, and trustworthy person asks the most questions. I think the person you should trust in a crisis should be someone who’s most doubtful. A personal rule of thumb is if someone seems to be so optimistic and believing of a product or solution, run. I think an ethical expert knows better that their solution is not perfect. The more confident you are with something, the more doubtful I am with it. This isn’t something new that everyone just realized, I just happen to give it a proper thought today.</p>

<p>Trust is a big scary word. In a paranoid sense, who do you trust with your personal data online when your behavior has been commodified and used by a few rich oligarchs to control the narrative of the world? In a personal sense, what happens if you let your walls down and be vulnerable; be naked and be awkward?</p>

<p>99% of the time, the answer to the personal sense of trust is nothing. 50% maybe it’ll make you happier and more fulfilled. But in a crisis, what if, what if the remaining 1% happens? What kind of mitigation steps do you have? What is your threat model? What are you willing to lose? To what extent are you willing to risk it all, for security? For a sense of stability?</p>

<p>Even if it’s a lost cause, will you stay with the sinking ship? Will you steer the wheel of a one-way relationship? Will you change your name, will you cover your face, will you cut your hair and will you move in order to keep the ship afloat? Is this faith? Is this loyalty? Is this based on trust? Or are you naive, dear? Do you let people run you over, do what is expected of you, denying yourself?</p>

<p>This is why my friends think I’m insane.</p>

<p>Hey, look, funny meme:</p>

<style>
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery li {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 250px;}
    .image-gallery li a {text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important; color: #777;}
    .image-gallery li a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery li a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
</style>

<ul class="image-gallery">
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <li>
        <a href="/assets/meme/dream%20big.jpeg" title="dream big">
            <img src="/assets/meme/dream big.jpeg" alt="dream big" class="figure" title="dream big" />
        </a>
    </li>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-20-may-journal-20" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-20-may-journal-20</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-20-may-journal-20"><![CDATA[<p>If you could associate a song with the impermanence of human relationship, what would it be?</p>

<p>My personal answer is This Is Not Enough by Hammock.</p>

<p>I think I mentioned that song before. It’s in B major, 3/4 time signature, the chord progression is pretty simple. It’s your usual I - IV - vi - V but they way it’s arranged makes it very beautiful and special to me. The instrumental break near the end is just top notch. I’m always lost having this scenario in my head where flashes of memories spent with my loved ones just play like a movie reel, as if I’m going to fucking die lmao.</p>

<p>Hey, good song. I recommend it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-21-may-journal-21" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T01:12:31+07:00</updated><id>https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-21-may-journal-21</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sxwvn.github.io/blog/2025-05-21-may-journal-21"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a long, long, way home. I need to rest and let my mortal flesh adjust to the new environment. That’s the nice scenario. Unfortunately I need to lock the fuck in again. What a life.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>